Register to The Charles Ives Papers
Yale University Music Library
- Ives's Collection of Music by Others, Series IX; 2 boxes
  - Music Library, IX.A
    - Octavo Church Music
      - Finale with markings and translation of lyric by Charles Ives (Box 60, Folder 7)
      - Fourteen Celebrated Marches, Mendelssohn (Box 60, Folder 7)
      - A Twilight Picture, Shelley, Percy Bysshe, 1792-1822 (Box 60, Folder 7)
      - Unidentified work (Box 60, Folder 7)
        p. 1, 2 missing
    - Organ
      - March from Leonora, Raff (Shelley) (Box 60, Folder 8)
        Signed "CEIves/March '05" on cover
      - Concert Variations on the Austrian Hymn for the Organ, Paine, John K. (Box 60, Folder 8)
        Autograph program back cover
      - La Pastorella, Nevin, Ethelbert, 1862-1901 (Box 60, Folder 8)
        Markings by ?
      - Grand Fantasia in E minor (The Storm), Lemmens, J. (Box 60, Folder 8)
        Markings Charles Ives
      - Marche Célèbre from Orchestral Suite, Lachner (Lux) (Box 60, Folder 8)
        Arranged for organ
      - Zampa Overture, Herold (Box 60, Folder 8)
        Four hands, markings Charles Ives
      - Ave Maria, arranged for organ, Henselt (Bartlett) (Box 60, Folder 8)
      - Das Ferne Land, Henselt (Leavitt) (Box 60, Folder 9)
      - The Marv'lous War, Haydn (Hiles) (Box 60, Folder 9)
      - Torchlight March, Guilmant (Warren) (Box 60, Folder 9)
      - Prayer, Guilmant (Box 60, Folder 9)
      - Two Amens (Box 60, Folder 9)
      - Funeral March (Box 60, Folder 9)
      - Melody (Box 60, Folder 9)
      - Anthem (Box 60, Folder 9)
      - First Sonata (Box 60, Folder 9)
      - Marche Pontificale, Gounod, Charles, 1818-1893 (Box 60, Folder 10)
      - Variations on "Pleyel's Hymn", Gerrish, Ch. (Box 60, Folder 10)
      - Adagio in F (Box 60, Folder 10)
        Fumagalli, Polibio
      - Symphonie No. 5, Dvorák, Juon Paul (Box 60, Folder 10)
        Markings Charles Ives 2nd movement
      - Grand Sortie from Ninth Symphony, Beethoven (Batiste) (Box 60, Folder 10)
      - Adagio from Fifth Symphony, Beethoven (Batiste) (Box 60, Folder 10)
      - Larghetto from Second Symphony, Beethoven (Batiste) (Box 60, Folder 10)
      - Variations on Scotch Air, Buck, Dudley, 1839-1909 (Box 60, Folder 11)
      - Home, Sweet Home, Buck (Box 60, Folder 11)
      - Holy Night (Box 60, Folder 11)
      - Overture to William Tell, Rossini (Buck) (Box 60, Folder 11)
      - Overture to Stradella, Flotow (Buck); incomplete (Box 60, Folder 11)
      - The Garland, Mendelssohn; vocal (Box 60, Folder 12)
      - Sally in Our Alley, Carney; incomplete (Box 60, Folder 12)
      - The Church and Concert Organist (Box 60, Folder 13)
        Bound collection
        Markings not Charles Ives
      - Rink's Practical Organ School, ed. Best, W.T. (Box 61, Folder 1)
      - Organ Works, Vol. 2, Bach, Johann Sebastian, 1685-1750 (Box 61, Folder 2)
      - Organ Works, Vol. 3, fragments, Bach, Johann Sebastian, 1685-1750 (Box 61, Folder 3)
      - Gems for the Organ, Collection, ed. Jackson, Samuel (Box 61, Folder 4)
      - Liszt Organ Method, Dulcken, Ferdinand (Box 61, Folder 5)
      - The Organist's Journal, Collections, Vols. 1, 2, 3 (Box 61, Folder 6)
      - The Organist's Journal, Vols. 4, 5 (Box 61, Folder 7)
        Markings
      - The Organist's Journal, Vols. 5, 6 (Box 61, Folder 8)
      - Pages from The Music of the Modern World (Box 61, Folder 9)
      - Fugue No. 6, Bach, Johann Sebastian, 1685-1750 (Box 61, Folder 9)
        Text and music pp 89-284 (some missing)
      - Rhapsody in Blue, Gershwin (Box 61, Folder 10)
        Memo on cover by Charles Ives: "Sent to me, through the book-binder friend of GG's-with GG's respects/May 1934/?/NY"
      - Favorite Reels, Jigs, and Hornspipes for the Violin, arr. Rollinson (Box 61, Folder 11)
      - L'Après midi d'un faune, Debussy, Claude, 1862-1918 (Box 61, Folder 12)
    - Piano
      - The High School Cadets March, Sousa (Box 61, Folder 13)
        For piano
      - The Directorate March, Sousa (Box 61, Folder 13)
      - The Liberty Bell March, Sousa (Box 61, Folder 13)
      - Il Bacio Waltz, Lanner, Fr. (Box 61, Folder 14)
      - Tarentelle, Heller, Stephen (Box 61, Folder 14)
        Markings Charles Ives?
      - Miscellaneous pages of music, copies (Box 61, Folder 15)
        With Charles Ives marginalia
        Originals with Earl Gilmore
  - West Redding House, IX.B
    In a music cabinet in the studio at West Redding are additional items of printed music by other composers either bought by or given to Ives. The drawers are numbered 1-62; some are empty. This listing conforms to the drawer numbers. It was made by Vivian Perlis in 1978.
    - 2 and 3 Part Inventions (ed. F.A. Roitzsch; penciled organ manuals and fingerings), Bach, Johann Sebastian, 1685-1750
    - Danse Ecossais (piano solo, 1880), Baker, Fred T.
    - Sonatas, vol. 1 (Schirmer, ed. Bulow & Lebert), Beethoven, Ludwig van, 1770-1827
    - Sonata, op. 14, no. 1, Beethoven, Ludwig van, 1770-1827
    - Suite for Viola & Piano (Schirmer), Bloch, Ernest, 1880-1959
    - Sonata, F minor, op. 5 (Universal), Brahms, Johannes, 1833-1897
    - Piano Solo Transcription of D Major Symphony (Simrock), Brahms, Johannes, 1833-1897
    - West Redding House
    - Children's Corner (Durand 1908), Debussy, Claude, 1862-1918
    - West Redding House
    - Three Impression of London (Piano solo; Boston Music Co. 1911), Grovlez, Gabriel
    - Gavotte in D (Schirmer 1909), Glazunov, Aleksandr Konstantinovich, 1865-1936
    - Nature Poems, op. 25 (piano solo, Chester 1920), Goossens, Eugene, 1893-1962
    - Marche Funèbre (Schirmer), Gounod, Charles, 1818-1893
    - Scherzo (Orchestral score, Peters 1894), Goldmark, Carl, 1830-1915
    - An den Frühling (piano solo, Schirmer 1898), Grieg, Edvard, 1843-1907
    - Elegie from Two Piano Pieces, op. 17 (Oliver Ditson 1917), Gabrilowitsch, Ossip, 1878-1936
    - Room-Music Tid-Bits, Grainger, Percy, 1882-1961
    - Nr. 3 Walking Tune (Schott 1912), Grainger, Percy, 1882-1961
    - In a Nutshell, Suite of 4 Pieces (piano solo, Schirmer 1916), Grainger, Percy, 1882-1961
    - Shepherd's Hey (piano solo, Schirmer 1911), Grainger, Percy, 1882-1961
    - New Music, July 1938 (one page only beside cover)
    - Saraband and Prelude, Harrison, Lou, 1917-2003
    - How Do You Like This?, Cleghorn, James
    - Gipsy Rondo (Kunkel, 1887), Haydn, Joseph, 1732-1809
    - Deuxième Sonate (violin and piano, Mathot 1912), Kriens, Christiaan, 1881-1934
      "à mon ami et compositeur illustre Charles E. Ives en bon souvenir de Christiaan Kriens, 5 Fevrier 1924" inscribed on cover
    - Sonate (violin and piano, Bellon), Lekeu, Guillaume, 1870-1894
      Includes letter from Reber Johnson
    - Symphony #3 (orchestra score, Peters), Mendelssohn
    - Sonata in G Minor (violin and piano, Schirmer 1913), Mason, Daniel Gregory, 1873-1953
    - Some Songs (Wolfenbüttel), Schubert
    - Sonate, op. 84 (violin and piano, Bote & Bock 1905), Reger
    - Evocation no. 4 (chant and piano, New Music, Jan. 1945), Ruggles
    - Organum (arr. for piano by J. Kirkpatrick), Ruggles
      Mail tube from Ruggles to Ives
    - Scherzo Vif (piano and violin, Mathot 1913), Schmitt, Florent
    - Meditation (piano and violin, Durand 1914), Schmitt, Florent
    - Streich quartet in D moll, op. 74 (Schirmer 1904), Reger
    - 43 Leichte Klavierstücke, op. 68., Schumann, Robert, 1810-1856
    - Nr. 43 Präludium u. Fuge (Schuberth)
    - Nr. 1 Air (Presser 1885)
    - Six new studies, Czerny, Carl, 1791-1857
    - Berceuse from "L'Oiseau de Feu" (piano, Boston Music Co. 1917), Stravinsky, Igor, 1882-1971
    - Sonata, op. 66 (piano, Elkan 1909), Scott, Cyril, 1879-1970
    - Lose Blätter, op. 13 (Schott 1910), Reger
    - Sonate in Fis moll (piano, Breitkopf), Scharwenka, Philipp
    - Morceaux, op. 26, no. 3, Chant d'Amour (Presser), Stojowski, Sigismund, 1870-1946
    - Sonate in Fis moll (piano and violin, Breitkopf), Scharwenka, Philipp
    - The Opening of the Piano, from 4 Picturesque Pieces for Ambitious Young Pianists (Riker, Brown & Wellington 1931), Slonimsky, Nicolas, 1894-1995
    - Dreams and Drums, from same Kiddies on the Keys, Slonimsky, Nicolas, 1894-1995
    - Six Etudes (Boston Music Co. 1917), Scriabin, Aleksandr Nikolayevich, 1872-1915
    - Sonate no. 4, Fis, op. 30 (Belaieff 1904), Scriabin, Aleksandr Nikolayevich, 1872-1915
    - Sonate no. 5, op. 53 (1909), Scriabin, Aleksandr Nikolayevich, 1872-1915
    - Sonate no. 8, op. 66 (Forberg), Scriabin, Aleksandr Nikolayevich, 1872-1915
    - Sonate no. 9, op. 68 (Forberg), Scriabin, Aleksandr Nikolayevich, 1872-1915
    - Pulchinelle, op. 3, no. 4 (Schirmer 1898), Rachmaninoff
    - Moments-tone poems for piano (Birchard 1930), Rudhyar
    - 2nd Sonata op. 118 (violin and piano, Durand 1917), Fauré, Gabriel, 1845-1924
    - Sonate en re mineur (violin and piano, Lerolle 1909), Roussel, Albert
    - Sonate (piano and violin, Durand 1909), Grovlez, Gabriel
    - Choral Triptych (Birchard 1934), Whitmer
    - Caprice Viennois (violin and piano, Fischer 1910), Kreisler, Fritz, 1875-1962
    - Sonate, op. 59 (violin part only), D'Indy, Vincent
    - Sonata no. II (violin and piano, Winthrop Rogers 1917), Ireland, John, 1879-1962
    - West Redding House
    - Assorted articles, ads, form letters from societies, etc.
    - West Redding House
    - Birthday cards, etc.
    - "Three Native Composers," by Henry Cowell The New Freeman, May 3, 1930
    - West Redding House
    - Sea Pieces, op. 55 (piano, Schmidt 1898), MacDowell, Edward, 1860-1908
    - Two articles about Gershwin
    - 114 Songs
    - West Redding House
    - Two newspaper clippings
    - West Redding House
    - Bulletin of the Museum of Modern Art-August 1940 "Orozco Explains"
    - Das Wohltemperirte Clavier (piano 4 hands, Schott), Bach, Johann Sebastian, 1685-1750
    - One Christmas card
    - West Redding House
    - West Redding House
    - New York Herald Tribune clipping re theater in New York
    - West Redding House
    - Gershwin clippings New York World-Telegram
      Also introductory order form for Yale Review and letter to Harmony Twichell Ives from English Speaking Union and Thoreau Society Bulletin
    - Clipping about Russian music
    - Russian National Anthem on which Charles Ives wrote "up and down nice little sugar plum"
    - Cartoons from Newspaper
    - Danbury New Times advertising "Boy Violinist R. Ricci"
    - Clipping New York Times of Koussevitsky
    - West Redding House
    - Letter to Charles Ives from Who's Who
    - West Redding House
    - 114 Songs Charles Ives
    - Insurance Pamphlet
    - Envelope 1948 from New York State Emergency Food Commission
    - Pamphlet Lincoln and The Sanitary Commission
    - The Banner
    - Article "High Frequency Resistance Standard"
    - Clipping New York World Telegram "Justice for All," Koussevitzky blurb, article about Schoenberg Newscast, Prentice Hall letter ad. for Bach publication for organists. Ives and Myrick envelope, page about pitch, frequency (loudness)
    - Card from the Valley Music Press
    - West Redding House
    - The Banner 3 copies, more drawings of ladies- Evening News, Ives and Myrick Pamphlet The Spectator, clipping Danbury Evening News, clipping an article by Sarah Ives, Picture of string quintet, ad for Heigman Department Store, testimony of William Anderson, newspaper ad
    - West Redding House
    - Envelope and small tool [?]
    - Blank manuscript paper
- Miscellaneous, Series X; 9 boxes
  - Miscellaneous, X.A
    - Miscellaneous (Box 62)
      Large collection of folders, envelopes, cover sheets used for storage and filing by Ives with autograph identifications and marginalia.
  - Miscellaneous, X.B
    - Miscellaneous (Box 63)
      Large collection of folders formerly used by library with Kirkpatrick identifications and information.
  - Miscellaneous, X.C
    - Miscellaneous (Box 64)
      Correspondence and information relating to Ives Oral History Project. The tapes of interviews with sixty people who worked with or knew Ives may be found at the Library; copies with Oral History, American Music Project directed by Vivian Perlis.
      Transcripts also with Oral History, American Music Project.
      See also: Charles Ives Remembered, an Oral History by Perlis. New Haven: Yale University Press, 1974. Paperback: New York: W.W. Norton.
  - Library Correspondence, X.D
    - 1956-1965 (Box 65, Folder 1)
    - 1956-1965 (Box 65, Folder 2)
    - 1966-1972 (Box 65, Folder 3)
    - 1966-1967 (Box 65, Folder 4)
    - 1968-1970 (Box 65, Folder 5)
    - 1968-1970 (Box 65, Folder 6)
    - 1971-1974 (Box 66, Folder 7)
    - 1974 (Box 66, Folder 8)
    - 1974 (Box 66, Folder 9)
    - 1974 (Box 66, Folder 10)
    - 1975 (Box 66, Folder 11)
    - 1976 (Box 66, Folder 12)
    - 1977-1978 (Box 66, Folder 13)
    - 1979 (Box 67, Folder 14)
    - Library Correspondence (Box 67, Folder 15)
    - Library Correspondence (Box 67, Folder 16)
    - Library Correspondence (Box 67, Folder 17)
    - Library Correspondence (Box 67, Folder 18)
    - 1967-1968 (Box 67, Folder 19)
    - 1961-1965 (Box 67, Folder 20)
    - 1956-1968 (Box 67, Folder 21)
    - 1968-1973 (Box 67, Folder 22)
    - Library Correspondence (Box 67, Folder 23)
    - 1956-1965 (Box 67, Folder 24)
    - 1965-1969 (Box 67, Folder 25)
    - 1955-1966 (Box 67, Folder 26)
    - 1975 (Box 67, Folder 27)
  - Miscellaneous, X.E
    Sub-series X.E is no longer in use
  - Miscellaneous, X.F
    - Relating to Ives music elsewhere (Library of Congress list, U Miss, etc.) (Box 70, Folder 1)
    - 3 x 5 cards with jottings by Amelia Van Wyck relating to genealogy (Box 70, Folder 2)
    - Lists of West Redding books made by Perlis class, 1979 (Box 70, Folder 3)
    - Catalogue lists (Box 70, Folder 4)
    - Unidentified, other (Box 70, Folder 5)